Register of the Fred M. Hechinger Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1955-1991.
  - Weaver, H. B., Mrs., 1981 (Folder 14: 36)
  - West Chester Area School District, 1980-1981 (Folder 14: 37)
  - WICAT, Inc., 1978 (Folder 14: 38)
  - Willis, Charles L., 1981 (Folder 14: 39)
  - WNYC, 1986-1989 (Folder 14: 40)
  - Wolfe, Doris, 1984 (Folder 14: 41)
  - Wolff, Clarence, Mrs., 1978 (Folder 14: 42)
  - World Affairs Council of Philadelphia, 1979-1980 (Folder 14: 43)
  - Woudenberg, Richard, 1977 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - Yale University, 1969-1990 (Folder 15: 2)
  - Yeshiva University, undated (Folder 15: 3)
- Speeches and Writings, 1947-1990.; See also Newspaper Columns File, Oversize File, and Scrapbooks
  Articles, books, comments, correspondence, reviews, and speeches, arranged chronologically by title.
  - General (Folder 15: 4-5)
    - Correspondence
      - 1961-1976 (Folder 15: 6)
      - 1977-1979 (Folder 15: 7)
      - 1980-1983 (Box-folder 16: 1)
      - 1984-1985 (Folder 16: 2)
      - 1986-1990 (Folder 16: 3)
    - Requests to grant reprints
      - 1961-1977 (Folder 16: 4)
      - 1978-1987 (Folder 16: 5)
    - Requests to speak or write
      - Accepted
        - 1961-1970 (Folder 16: 6)
        - 1971-1976 (Box-folder 17: 1)
        - 1977–1978 (Folder 17: 2)
        - 1979 (Folder 17: 3)
        - 1980 (Folder 17: 4)
        - 1981 (Folder 17: 5)
        - 1982 (Box-folder 18: 1)
        - 1983 (Folder 18: 2)
        - 1984 January-May (Folder 18: 3)
        - 1984 July – 1985 December (Folder 18: 4)
        - 1986-1987 (Folder 18: 5)
        - 1988-1990 (Box-folder 19: 1)
      - Declined
        - 1960-1976 (Folder 19: 2)
        - 1977 (Folder 19: 3)
        - 1978 (Folder 19: 4)
        - 1979
          - January-June (Folder 19: 5)
          - July-December (Folder 19: 6)
        - 1980 (Box-folder 20: 1)
        - 1981
          - January-June (Folder 20: 2)
          - July-December (Folder 20: 3)
    - Requests to speak or write
      - Declined
        - 1982 (Folder 20: 4)
        - 1983 (Folder 20: 5)
        - 1984 (Box-folder 21: 1)
        - 1985
          - February-April (Folder 21: 2)
          - June-December (Folder 21: 3)
        - 1986
          - January-July (Folder 21: 4)
          - October-November (Folder 21: 5)
        - 1987
          - March-May (Folder 21: 6)
          - June-December (Box-folder 22: 1)
        - 1988-1990 (Folder 22: 2)
    - Reviews and comments about Fred Hechinger
      - Undated (Folder 22: 3)
      - 1959-1972 (Folder 22: 4)
      - 1976 (Folder 22: 5)
      - 1977 (Folder 22: 6)
      - 1978 (Folder 22: 7)
      - 1979
        - January-March (Folder 22: 8)
        - April-December (Box-folder 23: 1)
      - 1980 (Folder 23: 2)
      - 1981 (Folder 23: 3)
      - 1982 (Folder 23: 4)
      - 1983 (Folder 23: 5)
      - 1984 (Folder 23: 6)
      - 1985-1986 (Folder 23: 7)
      - 1987 February – 1988 March (Folder 23: 8)
      - 1988 June – 1990 (Folder 23: 9)
  - "Assignment: Mission of the Independent School," Views from Penn Charter, undated. (Box-folder 24: 1)
    Printed copy
  - "The Battle for the German Youth," Harper's Magazine, undated. (Folder 24: 2)
  - "British School Broadcasts,", undated. (Folder 24: 3)
  - "Cancer Is Curable,", undated. (Folder 24: 4)
  - Comments, graduating class, undated. (Folder 24: 5)
  - "Education and Survival,", undated. (Folder 24: 6)
  - Excerpts from commencement speeches, undated. (Folder 24: 7)
    Galley
  - "Isolationism Versus National Purpose," address, Terminal Fulbright Conference, undated. (Folder 24: 8)
  - "License Commissioners Fielding,", undated. (Folder 24: 9)
  - "Mother of Engineering Education Revisited,", undated. (Folder 24: 10)
  - Participant, panel discussion, "What Is the Student Really Like?" Annual Meeting of the National Association of College Stores, Chicago, undated. (Folder 24: 11)
    Typescript and press release
  - "Readers' Adviser,", undated. (Folder 24: 12)
  - Remarks, First Annual Public Affairs Conference, Labor Relations in the American Economy, sponsored by the Yale Law School Student Association, undated. (Folder 24: 13)
  - Remarks, National Conference: New Dimensions for Educating Youth, undated. (Folder 24: 14)
  - Review of James B. Conant, Better Junior High School, undated. (Folder 24: 15)
  - Review of Sinclair Lewis, Kingsblood Royal, undated. (Folder 24: 16)
  - "Roosevelt College: An Experiment in Democracy,", undated. (Folder 24: 17)
  - "School Begins at Home,", undated. (Folder 24: 18)
  - "Summer Course in Democracy,", undated (Folder 24: 19)
  - "An Uncertain Path: Forty Years of Educational Technology,", undated. (Folder 24: 20)
  - "Library Psychiatrist," This Week Magazine, 1947 February 9. (Folder 24: 21)
  - "The Problem of German Re-education," Military Government Journal, 1948 January. (Folder 24: 22)
  - Review of Arthur Bliss Lane, I Saw Poland Betrayed, Saturday Review, 1948 March 6. (Folder 24: 23)
  - "Report on Education in Germany-1948,", 1948 November. (Folder 24: 24)
    Typescript and letter from Alonzo G. Grace
  - "All the News that Fits the Pattern," Harper's Magazine, 1949 May. (Folder 24: 25)
  - "The Indestructible Dr. Schacht," The Reporter, 1949 October 11. (Folder 24: 26)
  - "The Textbook Problem," Saturday Review, 1952 April 19. (Folder 24: 27)
  - "Moscow, Prague, and Israel," The Reporter, 1953 January 20. (Folder 24: 28)
  - "Interpreting Education to the Public," remarks, Fourteenth Annual Forum on Education of the Tuition Plan, New York, 1954 February 10. (Folder 24: 29)
  - "The Battle of Truth," Saturday Review, 1954 February 20. (Folder 24: 30)
  - "Can Yugoslavia Stay Communist?" This Week Magazine, 1954 October 10. (Folder 24: 31)
  - "Balkan Bulwark," This Week Magazine, 1954 November 28. (Folder 24: 32)
  - "Good King Haakon," THIS WEEK Magazine, 1955 November 6. (Folder 24: 33)
  - An Adventure in Education: Connecticut Points the Way, 1956; See also Scrapbooks (Folder 24: 34)
    Printed copy and reviews.
  - "Unlearning for the Future," Kenyon Alumni Bulletin, 1956 Spring. (Folder 24: 35)
  - "Wanted: Quality as Well as Quantity," Saturday Review, 1956 September 8. (Folder 24: 36)
  - "New Year: New Problems," Saturday Review, 1957 September 14. (Folder 24: 37)
  - "A Personal Message to College Students," American Council on Education, 1958. (Folder 24: 38)
  - Worrying About College?, 1958. (Folder 24: 39)
  - "Why Vassar?" Woman's Day, 1958 April. (Box-folder 25: 1)
  - Participant, panel discussion, Face the Nation, CBS Television, 1958 April 6. (Folder 25: 2)
  - Participant, Editors-Writers Conference on Testing, Princeton, New Jersey, 1958 May 13-14. (Folder 25: 3)
    Holograph and typescript
  - "Whither the American School?" Saturday Review, 1958 May 24. (Folder 25: 4)
  - Review of Eugene S. Wilson and Charles A. Bucher, College Ahead!, Amherst Alumni News, 1958 July. (Folder 25: 5)
  - Participant, The Open Mind, NBC Television, 1958 July 13. (Folder 25: 6)
  - "Is the School Crisis as Black as It's Painted?" Parents' Magazine and Better Homemaking, 1958 October. (Folder 25: 7)
  - Participant, The Open Mind, NBC Television, 1958 November 30. (Folder 25: 8)
  - The Big Red Schoolhouse, 1959.; See also Scrapbooks
    - General (Folder 25: 9)
    - Correspondence (Folder 25: 10)
    - Printed copy (Folder 25: 11)
    - Reviews (Folder 25: 12)
  - "The Ethical Culture Schools in American Education, 1878-1959," Teaching and Learning (Folder 25: 13)
  - "Higher Education and Survival," remarks, Quality and Opportunity in Higher Education, Second Regional Workshop on Higher Education, Western Interstate Commission for Higher Education, Boulder, Colorado, 1959. (Folder 25: 14)
  - Participant, The Open Mind, NBC Television, 1959 March 1. (Folder 25: 15)
  - "The Universal American Public School System," Vital Speeches, 1959 May 1. (Folder 25: 16)
  - "The All-American Picnic Is Over," address, Cubberley Lecture and Conference, Stanford University, California, 1959 July 22. (Folder 25: 17)
  - "A Cure for Growing Pains," Saturday Review, 1959 September 12. (Folder 25: 18)
  - Review of George Z. F. Bereday, William W. Brickman, and Gerald H. Read, eds., The Changing Soviet School, 1960? (Folder 25: 19)
  - "Education in a Time of Crisis," Hadassah Newsletter, 1960 April. (Folder 25: 20)
  - Commencement address, Wellesley College, Wellesley, Massachusetts, Wellesley College News, 1960 June 6. (Folder 25: 21)
    Typescript, printed copy, and related materials
  - "Big Changes Coming in Education," Parents' Magazine and Better Homemaking, 1960 September. (Folder 25: 22)
  - "Education Needs vs. Platform Promises," Challenge, 1960 October. (Folder 25: 23)
  - "The High School and the Public," California Journal of Secondary Education, 1960 October. (Folder 25: 24)
  - Remarks on education, Educational Media Study Panel, United States. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare, Washington, D.C., 1960 December 8. (Folder 25: 25)
    Typescript and correspondence
  - "Symbols of Understanding," Danish Foreign Office Journal, 1961. (Folder 25: 26)
    Printed copy and letter of appreciation from C. H. W. Hasselriis
  - "The American High School: Problems and Change," lecture, United States Information Agency, 1961 February? (Folder 25: 27)
    Typescript and letter from John G. H. Scoon
  - "Educational Changes in the United States From the Layman's Point of View," lecture, University of Puerto Rico, Puerto Rico, 1961 February 11. (Folder 25: 28)
  - Comments (with Grace Hechinger), quoted in an article by Edward T. Hall, Teachers College Record, 1961 March. (Folder 25: 29)
  - "Education and Survival," Institute for American Strategy, 1961 April. (Folder 25: 30)
  - "The University Presidency in Modern Society," address, United States. Congress. House of Representatives, 1961 April 18. (Folder 25: 31)
    Printed copy and letter from Richard W. Smith. Reprint, College and University Journal, 1962 Winter
  - "Excellence in Education" (with Grace Hechinger), Hadassah Magazine, 1961 May. (Folder 25: 32)
  - "Television and Education" (with Grace Hechinger), commentary on television, CBS Television Network, 1961 November. (Folder 25: 33)
  - "Should Your Daughter Go to College?" Woman's Day, 1962 February. (Folder 25: 34)
    Printed copy and letter from Harold C. Falkoff
  - "American Education: Change or Revolution," Frank Ellsworth Spaulding Lecture on Education, Yale University, Connecticut, 1962 February 1. (Box-folder 26: 1)
    Announcement. Includes printed copy of an interview by Alexander M. Hehmeyer, Yale News, 1962 February 2
  - "Education's Finest Hour," speech, American Textbook Publishers Institute, New York, 1962 March 23. (Folder 26: 2)
    Typescript and letter from Frank Redding
  - "The Story Behind the Strike," Saturday Review, 1962 May 19. (Folder 26: 3)
  - Article on college admission, Saturday Review, 1962 June 5? (Folder 26: 4)
  - "Trends in American Education," Yale Political, 1962 Summer. (Folder 26: 5)
  - "College Search," Literary Cavalcade, 1962 November. (Folder 26: 6)
  - Teen-Age Tyranny (with Grace Hechinger), 1963
    - Typescript (Folder 26: 7)
    - Printed copy (Folder 26: 8)
    - Reviews (Folder 26: 9-10)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 27: 1-2)
  - "Teaching Democratic Values,", 1963 February. (Folder 27: 3)
  - "Foreign Languages Stage a Comeback," Saturday Review, 1963 February 16. (Folder 27: 4)
    Printed copy and letter from Lawrence Hughes
  - "Years Ahead for Higher Education: The Picnic Is Over," Chapel Hill Weekly, 1963 March 27. (Folder 27: 5)
  - "The Future's Challenge to American Colleges,", 1963 April? (Folder 27: 6)
    Typescript, galley, and letter from Myra Dinnerstein
  - "A New Approach to Citizenship," Parents' Magazine and Better Homemaking, 1963 May. (Folder 27: 7)
    Printed fragment
  - "The Book Burners," review of Jack Nelson and Gene Roberts, Jr., The Censors and the Schools, The Reporter, 1963 June 6. (Folder 27: 8)
  - "A Failure, A New Beginning," The Reporter, 1963 July 18. (Folder 27: 9)
  - Interview of Charles Cogen, WCBS-TV, 1963 August 25. (Folder 27: 10)
    Typescript transcript and letter from Norman E. Walt, Jr.
  - "Dr. Conant's Bombshell," review of James B. Conant, The Education of American Teachers and of James D. Koerner, The Miseducation of American Teachers, The Reporter, 1963 September 26. (Folder 27: 11)
  - "The Prayer Controversy" (with Grace Hechinger), Hadassah, 1963 November. (Folder 27: 12)
    Printed copy and letter to Esther Gottesman
  - "New Directions in American Education," American Review, 1964? (Folder 27: 13)
  - "Introduction to Gloria Dapper Book," Public Relations for Educators, 1964 January? (Folder 27: 14)
    Typescript and letters from Gloria Dapper
  - "The Cities: Education,", 1964 January. (Folder 27: 15)
    Typescript and letters from Dorothy Carew
  - "The Plight of the City Schools," address, Harvard Colloquium, Harvard Divinity School, Massachusetts, 1964 January 30. (Folder 27: 16)
    Typescript and printed copy
  - "How Not to Waste College on Girls" (with Grace Hechinger), Parents' Magazine and Better Homemaking, 1964 February. (Folder 27: 17)
  - Article (with Grace Hechinger), McCall's, 1964 February 17? (Folder 27: 18)
    Typescript and letter from Peter Wyden
  - "Professor Shifts Called Harmful," reprinted from New York Times, 1964 March 8. (Folder 27: 19)
  - "Readin', Ritin', and Rafferty," The Reporter, 1964 April 9. (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - "Public Education: New York City," United States Information Agency, 1964 June? (Folder 28: 2)
  - "It Doesn't Have to Be Harvard or Vassar," Diners' Club Magazine, 1964 June. (Folder 28: 3)
  - Participant, "'Basic' Education Vs. 'Progressive'," discussion on Open Mind telecast, WNBC-TV, New York Post, 1964 November 8. (Folder 28: 4)
  - "Preferential Treatment for Negroes?" The Reporter, 1964 December 3. (Folder 28: 5)
  - "Technology's Challenge to Education," symposium, Saturday Review, 1964 December 12. (Folder 28: 6)
  - "The Mission of the Independent School," Andover Bulletin, 1964 Winter. (Folder 28: 7)
  - "Education 1964," Encyclopedia Year Book, Grolier, 1965. (Folder 28: 8)
    Typescript, galley, and letters from Dorothy Carew and Paul C. Tullier
  - "American Education," lecture, United States Information Agency, 1965 February. (Folder 28: 9)
  - "Education and Free Enterprise," address, Washington's Birthday Convocation, Washington College, Maryland, 1965 February 20. (Folder 28: 10)
    Typescript, printed copy, letter from Theodore F. Parker, and related materials
  - "Federal Aid to Education: Consensus and Controversy," Hadassah Magazine, 1965 March. (Folder 28: 11)
  - Opening address, Eighth Annual Williamsburg Student Burgesses Conference, Virginia, Daily Press and Richmond Times Dispatch, 1965 March 1. (Folder 28: 12)
    Typescript, printed copy, and letter from Thomas B. Schlesinger
  - Competence, Consequence, and Compassion," Michigan Quarterly Review, 1965 Spring. (Folder 28: 13)
  - "The Schools," Financial Times, 1965 April? (Folder 28: 14)
    Typescript, correspondence, and other materials
  - "Who Runs Our Big City Schools?" Saturday Review, 1965 April 17. (Folder 28: 15)
  - "Uncle Sam's Billion Dollar Push for Better Schools," Parents' Magazine and Better Homemaking, 1965 September. (Folder 28: 16)
  - "Pre-School Program: Head Start to Where?" Saturday Review, 1965 December 18. (Folder 28: 17)
    Printed copy and related materials
  - "Junior Colleges," Compton Year Book, Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1966? (Folder 28: 18)
  - "Activists on Campus," City College Alumnus, 1966. (Folder 28: 19)
  - Pre-School Education Today, ed., 1966. (Folder 28: 20)
    Printed copy and fragment, correspondence, review, and German translation
  - "Crisis in Our Municipal Colleges," City College Alumnus, 1966 January. (Folder 28: 21)
  - "A Look to the Century Ahead," St. Louis Post Dispatch, 1966 March 12. (Folder 28: 22)
    Typescript and printed review
  - "Advances in Education," Hadassah Magazine, 1966 May. (Folder 28: 23)
  - "The College Student: What's He Really Like?" Publishers' Weekly, 1966 May 16. (Folder 28: 24)
  - "Books in the Field: Education," Wilson Library Bulletin, 1966 November. (Folder 28: 25)
  - "Escalation, Ulcers, and Graduate Education," Fordham, 1966 December. (Folder 28: 26)
  - "Education," Living History of the World, 1967. (Folder 28: 27)
  - "Education: The Preschool Child," and "Education: Triumphs and Doubts," The Soviet Union: The Fifty Years, 1967. (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - Comments regarding the role of the independent school, Deerfield Academy, Deerfield, Massachusetts, 1967 Spring. (Folder 29: 2)
    Typescript and letter from William S. Litterick
  - Articles on Soviet education, 1967 August? (Folder 29: 3)
  - "Ten Years after Sputnik,", 1967 August? (Folder 29: 4)
  - "What Sputnik Did to Our Schools," McCalls's, 1967 October. (Folder 29: 5)
  - Participant, discussion on "The Electronic Revolution in the Classroom: Promise or Threat?" Council for Basic Education, Washington, D.C., 1967 October 27. (Folder 29: 6)
  - "The Student Threat to University Education," Outlook, 1967 Winter. (Folder 29: 7)
    Printed copy and letter from Edward S. Babcox, Jr.
  - "Education," Encyclopaedia Year Book, Grolier, 1968? (Folder 29: 8)
  - "Education," Year Book, Colliers-Crowell Educational Corporation, 1968? (Folder 29: 9)
  - "Education," World Book Year Book, 1968. (Folder 29: 10)
  - New York Times Guide to New York City Private Schools (with Grace Hechinger), 1968. (Folder 29: 11)
    Typescript, reviews, and related materials
  - "New York's Private Schools: Panic Among the Privileged," Saturday Review, 1968 March 16. (Folder 29: 12)
  - Interview, Paradoxian, 1968 Spring. (Folder 29: 13)
    Printed copy and letter from John Schreiber
  - Address, Ohio College Association Annual Meeting, Columbus, Ohio, 1968 April 6. (Folder 29: 14)
    Typescript and related materials, including biographical information on Fred Hechinger
  - "The Decline and Fall of the School Enrichment Programs," Council Woman, 1968 Fall. (Folder 29: 15)
  - Article on university administration, Change, 1968 November? (Folder 29: 16)
    Typescript, galley, and correspondence
  - "The Importance of a College or University to the Community," Wilkes College Alumnus, 1968 December. (Folder 29: 17)
    Printed copy, letter from Samuel M. Davenport, and related materials
  - "An Anti-Jewish Joke," review of Philip Roth, Portnoy's Complaint, 1969. (Folder 29: 18)
  - Comments on Herbert Kohl, The Open Classroom, New York Times, 1969. (Folder 29: 19)
  - "Education," Encyclopaedia Year Book, Grolier, 1969. (Folder 29: 20)
  - "William Bradley Otis," The Reader's Digest, 1969 March? (Folder 29: 21)
    Typescript and letter from Walter R. Fox
  - "Campus Protests and the Threat to Academe," City College Alumnus, 1969 March. (Folder 29: 22)
  - Inaugural lecture, James H. Case, Jr., Memorial Lecture, Bard College, New York, 1969 March 5. (Folder 29: 23)
    Typescript, galley, letter from Annys Wilson, and related materials
  - "The Ingredients of a Great Teacher," City College Alumnus, 1969 April. (Folder 29: 24)
  - "Jeopardy of Campus Democracy," address, New York City Hofstra Council, New York, 1969 May 28. (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Quotes in Wall Street Journal, 1969 June 30. (Folder 30: 2)
  - "Education and Public Opinion,", 1969 August? (Folder 30: 3)
    Typescript and letter from Lester Markel
  - "Advice for Students: How to Change Your Image," Alma Mater, 1969 October. (Folder 30: 4)
    Typescript, printed copy, and letter from Richard C. Underwood
  - Introduction: "How to Run a School Newspaper,", 1969 November? (Folder 30: 5)
    Typescript and letter from Donnie Brown
  - "Education," Encyclopedia Year Book, Grolier, 1970. (Folder 30: 6)
  - "Education," Year Book, Crowell-Collier Educational Corporation, 1970. (Folder 30: 7)
  - "Summerhill," chapter, Summerhill: for and Against, 1970. (Folder 30: 8)
    Typescript, Printed copy, and correspondence
  - "Don't Blame the Messenger," City College Alumnus, 1970 June. (Folder 30: 9)
  - "The Medium's Message for Education," Council Woman, 1970 July-September. (Folder 30: 10)
  - "Academic Freedom in America," Change, 1970 November-December. (Folder 30: 11)
    Typescript, printed copy, and letter from Edwin Kiester, Jr.
  - "Education: A National View," remarks, 1970 December 16. (Folder 30: 12)
  - "Education," Stravon Educational Press, 1971? (Folder 30: 13)
    Galley and letter from Robert H. Doherty
  - "Education," Encyclopaedia Year Book, Grolier, 1971. (Folder 30: 14)
    Typescript and letter from Helen Hynson Merrick
  - "Education," Year Book, Crowell-Collier Educational Corporation, 1971. (Folder 30: 15)
    Typescript and letters from Maron L. Waxman
  - "Education," Year Book, Field Enterprises Educational Corporation, 1971. (Folder 30: 16)
    Galley and letter from Paul C. Tullier
  - "Educational Change: Expansion in Numbers, Extension of Opportunities," American Red Cross Youth Journal, 1971 April. (Folder 30: 17)
    Galley, printed copy, and correspondence
  - "Crisis in Our Colleges,", 1971 September? (Folder 30: 18)
    Galley and correspondence
  - "The Challenge: De-Bureaucratizing Without De-Schooling," Perspectives on Education, Teachers College, Columbia University, 1971 Fall. (Folder 30: 19)
  - "Television: Meanwhile on Sesame Street" (with Grace Hechinger), New York, 1971 October 25. (Folder 30: 20)
  - "Who's in Charge?" Change, 1971-1972 Winter. (Folder 30: 21)
    Galley, printed copy, and letters from Cheryl Bentsen
  - "Education," Year Book, Field Enterprises Educational Corporation, 1972. (Folder 30: 22)
  - "Open University" (with Grace Hechinger)?, 1972. (Folder 30: 23)
  - Comments on City College's role as a source of leaders in the communications field, City College Alumnus, 1972 January. (Folder 30: 24)
  - Commencement address, Belmont Hill School, Belmont, Massachusetts, 1972 June 8. (Folder 30: 25)
    Galley and related materials
  - "Private Schools: The Current Crisis" (with Grace Hechinger), Harper's Bazaar, 1972 September. (Box-folder 31: 1)
    Galley and printed copy
  - Remarks, conference, "The Improvement of Teaching in Higher Education," sponsored jointly by the Center for the Teaching Professions, Northwestern University, and the W. K. Kellogg Foundation, 1972 November 16-18. (Folder 31: 2)
  - Review of Mario D. Fantini, Public School of Choice: A Place for the Reform of American Education, Commonweal, 1973. (Folder 31: 3)
  - "ITT: A Nasty Analogy," The New Republic, 1973 April 28. (Folder 31: 4)
  - Address, Deerfield Academy, Deerfield, Massachusetts, 1973 May 27. (Folder 31: 5)
  - "How Necessary Are School Grades?" Weight Watchers, 1973 July. (Folder 31: 6)
  - "Sifting Revolution's Ashes for Salvage," National Observer, 1973 July 14. (Folder 31: 7)
    Galley, printed copy, and letter from Margaret Lefkowitz
  - Article, Educational Testing Service, New Jersey, 1973 November. (Folder 31: 8)
  - Articles on education, Year Book, Macmillan Educational Corporation, 1974. (Folder 31: 9)
    Typescript, galley, and a letter from Deborah Gale
  - Review (with Grace Hechinger) of Robert H. Bremmer, ed., Children and Youth in America, 1974. (Folder 31: 10-14)
  - "Should the Liberal Arts College Be Saved?...And if so, Why?" speech, Haverford's 140th Anniversary Celebration, 1974. (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - "Are Schools Better in Other Countries?" (with Grace Hechinger), American Education, 1974 January-February. (Folder 32: 2)
  - "SAT Scores: What Happened to the Best and the Brightest?" Saturday Review World, 1974 February 9. (Folder 32: 3)
  - "In the End Was the Euphemism," Saturday Review World, 1974 March 9. (Folder 32: 4)
  - "Colleges in Search of Freshmen," Saturday Review World, 1974 April 6. (Folder 32: 5)